Register of the Grand Duke George Letters to Princess Kseniia, 1914-1918
Hoover Institution Archives
Grand Duke George Letters to Princess Kseniia,
1914-1918
76101
George, Grand Duke of Russia, 1863-1919
2 manuscript boxes (0.8 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Relates to political and military conditions in Russia during World War I, the Russian Revolution, and family affairs. George, Grand Duke of Russia is also known as Georgii Mikhailovich, Grand Duke of Russia.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1976.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Scope and Content of Collection
Relates to political and military conditions in Russia during World War I, the Russian Revolution, and family affairs. George, Grand Duke of Russia is also known as Georgii Mikhailovich, Grand Duke of Russia.
Access Points
Romanov, House of.; World War, 1914-1918.; World War, 1914-1918--Russia.; Russia.; Soviet Union.; Russia--Court and courtiers.; Soviet Union--History--Revolution, 1917-1921.; Kseniia, Princess of Russia, 1903-
Container List
- Correspondence, 1914-1918
  - June -September 1914 (24 letters) (Box 1)
  - October -December 1914 (24 letters)
  - January -March 1915 (22 letters)
  - April -July 1915 (29 letters)
  - August -December 1915 (38 letters)
  - January -April 1916 (30 letters)
  - May -September 1916 (36 letters) (Box 2)
  - October -December 1916 (23 letters)
  - January -March 1917 (22 letters)
  - April -August 1917 (30 letters)
  - September -December 1917 (28 letters)
  - January -April 1917 (29 letters)
  - May -November 1918 (34 letters)